<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<useCase id="dronology-UC4">
    <name>Structural Fire Fighting</name>
    <description>Multiple UAVs dispatched to analyze the structure for fire fighting.</description>

    <actors>
        <actor>Drone Commander</actor>
        <actor>Semi-autonomous UAV</actor>
    </actors>

    <preconditions>
        <precondition>DroneResponse is running</precondition>
        <precondition>Multiple UAVs are equipped with cameras</precondition>
    </preconditions>

    <successEndConditions>
        <condition>The UAVs create and maintain a heatmap of the entire building</condition>
        <condition>All UAVs return to launch without damage at the end of the incident</condition>
    </successEndConditions>
    <failureEndConditions>
        <condition>A UAV collides with the building or ground</condition>
        <condition>The UAVs fail to provide an accurate heatmap of the building</condition>
    </failureEndConditions>

    <trigger>The Drone Commander activates the fire support mission.</trigger>

    <mainSequence>
        <step id="S1">Firefighters request flight authorization.</step>
        <step id="S2">UAVs are activated and armed.</step>
        <step id="S3">The UAVs perform synchronized takeoff.</step>
        <step id="S4">The UAVs use their onboard vision to create an initial mapping of the building.</step>
        <step id="S5">The UAVs plan optimized and coordinated surveillance flights around the building.</step>
        <step id="S6">Prior to each leg of the surveillance flight, each UAV leases the necessary airspace.</step>
        <step id="S7">Each UAV performs image capture and analysis using thermal imagery.</step>
        <step id="S8">Imagery from each UAV is continuously streamed and aggregated to create a current heatmap of the building.</step>
        <step id="S9">Steps 4-7 are repeated throughout the fire event.</step>
        <step id="S10">The Incident Commander ends the mission once the fire has been controlled.</step>
    </mainSequence>

    <errorSteps>
        <esteps id="E1" start="S7">
            <description>The UAV detects a possible victim at a confidence level below the 'victim_detected' threshold but above the lowest 'ignore_level'.</description>
            <step id="E1S1">The UAV raises an alert and requests victim confirmation from the human operator.</step>
            <step id="E1S2">The UAV continues to stream imagery.</step>
            <step id="E1S3">The human operator inspects the video stream.</step>
            <step id="E1S3.1">If the human operator believes that a victim may have been found, firefighters plan and execute a rescue mission.</step>
            <step id="E1S3.2">If the human operator rejects the candidate sighting, the UAV continues its currently assigned route.</step>
        </esteps>
    </errorSteps>
</useCase>
