<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<useCase id="dronology-SC2">
    <name>Active Tracking</name>
    <description>A UAV actively tracks a victim.</description>

    <actors>
        <actor>Semi-Autonomous UAV</actor>
        <actor>Mission Commander</actor>
    </actors>

    <preconditions>
        <precondition>UAV is within near vision-range of the victim</precondition>
        <precondition>UAV has actively tagged the victim</precondition>
    </preconditions>

    <successEndConditions>
        <condition>The UAV remains within near vision-range of the victim and streams video imagery to Emergency Responders</condition>
    </successEndConditions>
    <failureEndConditions>
        <condition>UAV fails to actively track the victim</condition>
    </failureEndConditions>

    <trigger>The UAV is assigned or assumes the task of tracking a person</trigger>

    <mainSequence>
        <step id="S1">The UAV positions itself in tracking_position, i.e., in the near vicinity of the victim but not directly overhead.</step>
        <step id="S2">The UAV uses image capture and analysis to continually tag the victim in the image stream.</step>
        <step id="S3">Based on the UAV's position (pitch, roll, yaw), the onboard tracker continually calculates the relative position of the victim with respect to the UAV.</step>
        <step id="S4">The onboard tracker generates appropriate velocity vectors to fly towards the victim, without flying directly over the victim and maintaining victim_separation_distance and always flying at an altitude greater than minimum_altitude.</step>
        <step id="S5">The velocity vector is sent to the UAV's autopilot and executed to enable the UAV to track the victim.</step>
        <step id="S6">Steps 2-5 are repeated until the UAV receives a stop_tracking command.</step>
    </mainSequence>

    <errorSteps>
        <esteps id="E1" start="S2">
            <description>The UAV loses track of the victim</description>
            <step id="E1S1">The UAV attempts to re-tag the victim by changing altitude and performing a localized search.</step>
        </esteps>
    </errorSteps>
</useCase>
