<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<useCase id="dronology-SC9">
    <name>Item Drop</name>
    <description>A UAV delivers an item such as a flotation device or defibrillator.</description>

    <actors>
        <actor>Semi-Autonomous UAV</actor>
        <actor>Mission Commander</actor>
    </actors>

    <preconditions>
        <precondition>The UAV is equipped with a carry-release mechanism based on either a parachute or a reel device.</precondition>
        <precondition>The weight of the item to be delivered is within the safe operating payload of the UAV.</precondition>
        <precondition>The item to be delivered has been attached to the UAV's carry mechanism.</precondition>
    </preconditions>

    <successEndConditions>
        <condition>The UAV successfully delivers the item to the assigned location.</condition>
    </successEndConditions>

    <failureEndConditions>
        <condition>The UAV fails to deliver the device to the assigned location.</condition>
        <condition>The UAV drops the item in an incorrect position or onto a person.</condition>
    </failureEndConditions>

    <trigger>The UAV receives a command to deliver the item.</trigger>

    <mainSequence>
        <step id="S1">The UAV takes-off and flies to the designated delivery coordinates.</step>
        <step id="S2">The UAV starts streaming video.</step>
        <step id="S3">The video is displayed in the UI for a human operator.</step>
        <step id="S4">The UAV uses image capture and analysis to determine a safe drop point appropriate for the task at hand.</step>
        <step id="S5">The UAV positions itself at the targeted drop point.</step>
        <step id="S6">The UAV requests permission from the human operator to drop the item.</step>
        <step id="S7">The human operator gives permission for the drop.</step>
        <step id="S8">The UAV lowers the item at the drop point.</step>
        <step id="S9">The human operator confirms that the drop is completed.</step>
        <step id="S10">The UAV moves to a safe observation point and awaits further instructions.</step>
    </mainSequence>

    <errorSteps>
        <esteps id="E1" start="S4">
            <description>The carry mechanism fails to activate when commanded.</description>
            <step id="E1S1">The operator attempts a manual command.</step>
            <step id="E1S2">If the carry mechanism continues to fail, the operator recalls the UAV.</step>
        </esteps>

        <esteps id="E2" start="S4">
            <description>The UAV is unable to find a safe drop point in the vicinity of the coordinates.</description>
            <step id="E2S1">The human operator uses the video stream to manually identify the drop point.</step>
        </esteps>

        <esteps id="E3" start="S7">
            <description>The operator refuses permission for the drop point proposed by the UAV.</description>
            <step id="E3S1">The operator suggests an alternate drop position or aborts the drop.</step>
        </esteps>
    </errorSteps>
</useCase>
