<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<useCase id="dronology-EC1">
    <name>Loss of Signal</name>
    <description>Without an onboard pilot, there is a significant reliance on the command and control link, and a greater emphasis on the loss of functionality associated with lost of signal. This exception case occurs when such a loss of signal occurs. Most UAVs have some degree of onboard autonomy - varying between the ability to continue flight to the currently assigned waypoint, execute failsafe mechanisms, and/or complete an entire mission autonomously.</description>

    <primaryActors>
        <actor>Ground Control System</actor>
        <actor>RPIC</actor>
        <actor>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle</actor>
    </primaryActors>
    <supportingActors>
        <actor>Air Traffic Control</actor>
    </supportingActors>

    <preconditions>
        <precondition>The UAV is in the air and has a command and control link to one or more ground control stations.</precondition>
        <precondition>A [failsafe] action has been established to activate RTL (Return to Launch) at a predefined altitude in case of loss-of-signal.</precondition>
    </preconditions>

    <successEndConditions>
        <condition>Signal is re-established and the flight continues.</condition>
        <condition>The UAV is landed safely despite the loss of signal.</condition>
        <condition>The UAV completes its mission autonomously despite loss of signal (currently not authorized by FAA).</condition>
    </successEndConditions>
    <failureEndConditions>
        <condition>The UAV is lost and/or crashes.</condition>
    </failureEndConditions>

    <trigger>The UAV is in flight and experiences a loss-of-signal event for greater than [loss_of_signal_threshold_seconds].</trigger>

    <mainSequence>
        <step id="S1">The UAV detects and responds to loss-of-signal.</step>
        <step id="S1.1">The UAV detects that it has lost communication with the ground control station.</step>
        <step id="S1.2">The failsafe mechanism is activated, and the UAV autonomously returns to launch (RTL) at its designated RTL altitude.</step>

        <step id="S2">DroneResponse responds to the loss-of-signal event.</step>
        <step id="S2.1">The runtime monitoring system detects the loss of signal event for the UAV.</step>
        <step id="S2.2">The runtime monitoring system raises an alert.</step>
        <step id="S2.3">The alert is displayed in the UI to notify the RPIC of the loss-of-signal event.</step>

        <step id="S3">The RPIC maintains visual line of sight with the UAV and observes that it has transitioned to RTL mode.</step>
        <step id="S4">If necessary, the UAV suspends the remainder of its mission or moves other UAVs out of the way of the returning UAV.</step>
    </mainSequence>

    <errorSteps>
        <esteps id="E1" start="S1">
            <description>No failsafe mechanism has been established onboard the UAV.</description>
            <step id="E1S1">If the UAV flies outside an established Geofence, the Geofence_failsafe is activated.</step>
        </esteps>
        <esteps id="E2" start="S2">
            <description>Multiple UAVs experience a simultaneous loss of signal and activate RTL simultaneously.</description>
            <step id="E2S1">Each UAV has a unique altitude assigned and returns home safely, avoiding collisions during RTL (optimistic scenario).</step>
            <step id="E2S2">Each UAV does not have a unique altitude assigned, increasing the risk of collisions during simultaneous RTL events.</step>
        </esteps>
        <esteps id="E3" start="S1.2">
            <description>Signal is re-established during RTL.</description>
            <step id="E3S1">ATC runs a diagnostic of each UAV's flight path and attempts to reserve airspace for the entire RTL route.</step>
            <step id="E3S2">When airspace cannot be reserved for the entire route, the UAV reserves airspace for as much of the route as available. The UAV mode is reset to FLYING.</step>
            <step id="E3S3">When the UAV reaches an intermediate waypoint, it attempts to reserve airspace for the remainder of the flight.</step>
            <step id="E3S4">Steps 4.2 and 4.3 are repeated until the UAV receives clearance to return home.</step>
        </esteps>
    </errorSteps>
</useCase>
